<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<resources>
    <string-array name="quotes">
        <item>A dog is not considered a good dog because he is a good barker. A man is not considered a good man because he is a good talker.</item>
        <item>A jug fills drop by drop.</item>
        <item>A man is not called wise because he talks and talks again; but if he is peaceful, loving and fearless then he is in truth called wise.</item>
        <item>A man should first direct himself in the way he should go. Only then should he instruct others.</item>
        <item>A man who will be the public leader, must know how to be the public follower.</item>
        <item>All descriptions of reality are temporary hypotheses.</item>
        <item>All know the way, but few actually walk it.</item>
        <item>All phenomena do not inherently exist because of being dependent-arisings. all phenomena do not inherently exist because of being dependently imputed.</item>
        <item>All things appear and disappear because of the concurrence of causes and conditions. Nothing ever exists entirely alone; everything is in relation to everything else.</item>
        <item>All wrong-doing arises because of mind. If mind is transformed can wrong-doing remain?</item>
        <item>Ambition is like love, impatient both of delays and rivals.</item>
        <item>An idea that is developed and put into action is more important than an idea that exists only as an idea.</item>
        <item>An insincere and evil friend is more to be feared than a wild beast; a wild beast may wound your body, but an evil friend will wound your mind.</item>
        <item>An outside enemy exists only if there is anger inside.</item>
        <item>Analyzing through special insight and realizing the lack of inherent existence constitute understanding of the signless.</item>
        <item>Anger will never disappear so long as thoughts of resentment are cherished in the mind. Anger will disappear just as soon as thoughts of resentment are forgotten.</item>
        <item>Anxiety shortens life.</item>
        <item>As a flower that is lovely and beautiful, but is scentless, even so fruitless is the well-spoken word of one who practices it not.</item>
        <item>As rain falls equally on the just and the unjust, do not burden your heart with judgments but rain your kindness equally on all. </item>
        <item>As you walk and eat and travel, be where you are. Otherwise you will miss most of your life.</item>
        <item>Attachment leads to suffering.</item>
        <item>Awake. Be the witness of your thoughts.</item>
        <item>Be a lamp unto yourself. Work out your liberation with diligence.</item>
        <item>Be greatly aware of the present.</item>
        <item>Be vigilant; guard your mind against negative thoughts.</item>
        <item>Be where you are; otherwise you will miss your life.</item>
        <item>Being deeply learned and skilled, being well-trained and using well-spoken words, this is good luck.</item>
        <item>Believe nothing, no matter where you read it, or who said it, no matter if I have said it, unless it agrees with your own reason and your own common sense.</item>
        <item>Better is to speak unpleasant truth than to tell lies.</item>
        <item>Better than a thousand hollow words is one word that brings peace.</item>
        <item>Chaos is inherent in all compounded things. Strive on with diligence.</item>
        <item>Clean, clear, calm; these are characteristics of a noble person.</item>
        <item>Conquer anger by love, evil by good; conquer the miser with liberality, and the liar with truth.</item>
        <item>Constant dripping wears away the stone.</item>
        <item>Contentment is the greatest wealth.</item>
        <item>Crying with the wise is better than laughing with the fool.</item>
        <item>Desire never crosses the path of virtuous and wakeful men.</item>
        <item>Dhamma (virtue) is systematic practice for a man at every stage of his life.</item>
        <item>Do not dwell in the past, do not dream of the future, concentrate the mind on the present moment.</item>
        <item>Do not look for a sanctuary in anyone except your self.</item>
        <item>Do not neglect recollection of death.</item>
        <item>Do not overrate what you have received, nor envy others. He who envies others does not obtain peace of mind.</item>
        <item>Don\'t escape when you have a problem because there always is a way to solve it
            .</item>
        <item>Doubt everything. Find your own light.</item>
        <item>Easy to do are things that are bad and harmful to oneself. But exceedingly difficult to do are things that are good and beneficial.</item>
        <item>Education is a guide, knowledge is the key.</item>
        <item>Endurance is one of the most difficult disciplines, but it is to the one who endures that the final victory comes.</item>
        <item>Ennui has made more gamblers than avarice, more drunkards than thirst, and perhaps as many suicides as despair.</item>
        <item>Even as a solid rock is unshaken by the wind, so are the wise unshaken by praise or blame.</item>
        <item>Even death is not to be feared by one who has lived wisely.</item>
        <item>Every human being is the author of his own health or disease.</item>
        <item>Every morning we are born again. What we do today is what matters most.</item>
        <item>Everyone may be a fool but nobody is a fool forever.</item>
        <item>Everything that has a beginning has an ending. Make your peace with that and all will be well.</item>
        <item>Failure teaches a man how to succeed.</item>
        <item>Fashion your life as a garland of beautiful deeds.</item>
        <item>Few among men are they who cross to the further shore. The others merely run up and down the bank on this side.</item>
        <item>Flattering words are honey-coated poison.</item>
        <item>Following the noble path is like entering a dark room with a light in the hand; the darkness will all be cleared away, and the room will be filled with light.</item>
        <item>Fools wait for a lucky day but every day is a lucky day for an industrious man.</item>
        <item>For the good of the many, for the happiness of the many, out of compassion for the world.</item>
        <item>Friendship is the only cure for hatred, the only guarantee of peace.</item>
        <item>From a withered tree, a flower blooms.</item>
        <item>Give thanks for what had been given to you, however little. Be pure, never falter.</item>
        <item>Good to forgive, the best to forget.</item>
        <item>Greed is an imperfection that defiles the mind; hate is an imperfection that defiles the mind; delusion is an imperfection that defiles the mind.</item>
        <item>Happiness comes when your work and words are of benefit to yourself and others.</item>
        <item>Happiness is a journey not a destination.</item>
        <item>Hatred does not cease by hatred, but only by love; this is the eternal rule.</item>
        <item>Have compassion for all beings, rich and poor alike; each has their suffering. Some suffer too much, others too little.</item>
        <item>He is able who thinks he is able.</item>
        <item>He who experiences the unity of life sees his own Self in all beings, and all beings in his own Self, and looks on everything with an impartial eye.</item>
        <item>He who loves 50 people has 50 woes; he who loves no one has no woes.</item>
        <item>Health is the greatest gift, contentment the greatest wealth, faithfulness the best relationship.</item>
        <item>Holding on to anger is like grasping a hot coal with the intent of throwing it at someone else; you are the one who gets burned.</item>
        <item>How easy it is to see your brother\'s faults. How hard it is to face your own.</item>
        <item>However many holy words you read, however many you speak, what good will they do you If you do not act on upon them.</item>
        <item>I do not believe in a fate that falls on men however they act; but I do believe in a fate that falls on them unless they act.</item>
        <item>I don\'t wish to be everything to everyone, but I would like to be something to
            someone.</item>
        <item>I never see what has been done; I only see what remains to be done.</item>
        <item>If a man\'s mind becomes pure, his surroundings will also become pure.</item>
        <item>If everything is gotten dreamily, it will go away dreamily too.</item>
        <item>If the selflessness of phenomena is analyzed and if this analysis is cultivated, it causes the effect of attaining nirvana through no other cause does one come to peace.</item>
        <item>If there is nothing that you like, you must like the things that you have.</item>
        <item>If we could see the miracle of a single flower clearly, our whole life would change.</item>
        <item>If we fail to look after others when they need help, who will look after us?</item>
        <item>If while on your way you meet no one your equal or better, steadily continue on your way alone. There is no fellowship with fools.</item>
        <item>If you do not change direction, you may end up where you are heading.</item>
        <item>If you find no one to support you on the spiritual path, walk alone. There is no companionship with the immature.</item>
        <item>If you light a lamp for somebody, it will also brighten your path.</item>
        <item>If you propose to speak always ask yourself, is it true, is it necessary, is it kind.</item>
        <item>If you truly loved yourself, you could never hurt another.</item>
        <item>If you wish to be gentle with others, be gentle first with yourself.</item>
        <item>If your compassion does not include yourself, it is incomplete.</item>
        <item>Ignorance is the real evil.</item>
        <item>In a controversy the instant we feel anger we have already ceased striving for the truth, and have begun striving for ourselves.</item>
        <item>In every trial let understanding fight for you.</item>
        <item>In separateness lies the world\'s greatest misery; in compassion lies the world\'s
            true strength.</item>
        <item>In the end\nthese things matter most:\nHow well did you love?\nHow fully did you live?\nHow deeply did you let go?</item>
        <item>In the sky, there is no distinction of east and west; people create distinctions out of their own minds and then believe them to be true.</item>
        <item>In this worldHate never yet dispelled hate\nOnly love dispels hate\nThis is the law Ancient and inexhaustible. You to shall pass away. Knowing this, how can you quarrel.</item>
        <item>Inward calm cannot be maintained unless physical strength is constantly and intelligently replenished.</item>
        <item>It is a man\'s own mind, not his enemy or foe, that lures him to evil ways.</item>
        <item>It is better to conquer yourself than to win a thousand battles. Then the victory is yours. It cannot be taken from you, not by angels or by demons, heaven or hell.</item>
        <item>It is better to do nothing than to do what is wrong. For whatever you do, you do to yourself.</item>
        <item>It is better to travel well than to arrive.</item>
        <item>It is easy to know man\'s face, but it is difficult to know his thought.</item>
        <item>It is flooded water that makes mud; it is clean water that wipes away mud.</item>
        <item>It is in a man\'s own mind, not his enemy or foe, that leads him to evil ways.</item>
        <item>Just as a candle cannot burn without fire, men cannot live without a spiritual life.</item>
        <item>Just to say \'I believe\' or \'I do not doubt\' does not mean that you understand and see. To force oneself to see and accept a thing without understanding is political and not spiritual or intellectual.</item>
        <item>Kindness should become the natural way of life, not the exception.</item>
        <item>Learn this from water: loud splashes the brook but the oceans depth are calm.</item>
        <item>Let a man avoid evil deeds as a man who loves life avoids poison. Let go of anger. Let go of pride.When you are bound by nothingYou go beyond sorrow.</item>
        <item>Let yourself be open and life will be easier. A spoon of salt in a glass of water makes the water undrinkable. A spoon of salt in a lake is almost unnoticed.</item>
        <item>Life is a river always flowing. do not hold onto things. work hard.</item>
        <item>Light dispels darkness. Wisdom dispels ignorance.</item>
        <item>Living without hope is like burying oneself.</item>
        <item>Long is the night to him who is awake; long is a mile to him who is tired; long is life to the foolish who do not know the true law.</item>
        <item>Look not for recognition but follow the awakened and set yourself free.</item>
        <item>Look not to the faults of others, nor to their omissions and commissions. But rather look to your own acts, to what you have done and left undone.</item>
        <item>Make of yourself a light.</item>
        <item>Mans death is the least of all things material. What is left to the world is virtues and vices.</item>
        <item>Master your words.\nMaster your thoughts.\nNever allow your body to do harm.\nFollow these three roads with purity\nAnd you will find yourself upon the one way, The way of wisdom.</item>
        <item>May all that have life be delivered from suffering.</item>
        <item>Meditation brings wisdom;lack of mediation leaves ignorance. Know well what leads you forward and what hold you back, and choose the path that leads to wisdom.</item>
        <item>Merit is to accumulated, evil is to be abandoned.</item>
        <item>More than those who hate you, more than all your enemies, an undisciplined mind does greater harm.</item>
        <item>Most problems, if you give them enough time and space, will eventually wear themselves out.</item>
        <item>Neither fire nor wind, birth nor death can erase our good deeds.</item>
        <item>Never speak harsh words, For they will rebound upon you.</item>
        <item>Angry words hurt, And the hurt rebounds.</item>
        <item>No one saves us but ourselves. No one can and no one may. We ourselves must walk the path.</item>
        <item>Nothing ever exists entirely alone; everything is in relation to everything else.</item>
        <item>Nothing is permanent except change.</item>
        <item>On a long journey of human life, faith is the best of companions; it is the best refreshment on the journey; and it is the greatest property.</item>
        <item>One is not low because of birth nor does birth make one holy. Deeds alone make one low, deeds alone make one holy.</item>
        <item>One thought leads to heaven, one thought leads to hell.</item>
        <item>Opinion, O disciples, is a disease; opinion is a tumor; opinion is a sore. He who has overcome all opinion, O disciples, is called a saint, one who knows.</item>
        <item>Our life is a creation of our mind.</item>
        <item>Our life is shaped by our mind; we become what we think.</item>
        <item>Our sorrows and wounds are healed only when we touch them with compassion.</item>
        <item>Our theories of the eternal are as valuable as are those that a chick which has not broken its way through its shell might form of the outside world.</item>
        <item>Pain is certain, suffering is optional.</item>
        <item>Peace comes from within. Do not seek it without.</item>
        <item>People with opinions just go around bothering one another.</item>
        <item>Physical charms attract the eyes, goodness attracts the mind.</item>
        <item>Poverty with dignity is better than wealth based on shame.</item>
        <item>Praise and blame, gain and loss, pleasure and sorrow come and go like the wind. To be happy, rest like a giant tree in the midst of them all.</item>
        <item>Rage is a powerful energy that with diligent practice can be transformed into fierce compassion. However much we disagree with our enemies. They too feel justified in their point of view.</item>
        <item>Rather than continuing to seek the truth, simply let go of your views.</item>
        <item>Remembering a wrong is like carrying a burden on the mind.</item>
        <item>Resolve to be tender with the young, compassionate with the aged, sympathetic with the striving and tolerant with the weak and wrong. Sometime in your life, you will have been all of these.</item>
        <item>Set your heart on doing good. Do it over and over again, and you will be filled with joy.</item>
        <item>She who knows life flows, feels no wear or tear, needs no mending or repair.</item>
        <item>Silence the angry man with love. Silence the ill-natured man with kindness. Silence the miser with generosity. Silence the liar with truth.</item>
        <item>Sorrow cannot touch the man who is not in the bondage of anything, who owns nothing.</item>
        <item>Speak or act with an impure mind and trouble will follow you.</item>
        <item>Speak the truth do not become angered and give when asked, even be it a little. By these three conditions one goes to the presence of the gods.</item>
        <item>Suppose an enemy has hurt you in his own domain, why should you annoy yourself and hurt your mind in your own domain?</item>
        <item>Teach this triple truth to all: A generous heart, kind speech, and a life of service and compassion are the things which renew humanity.</item>
        <item>The foot feels the foot when it feels the ground.</item>
        <item>The fragrance of sandalwood and rosebay does not travel far. But the fragrance of virtue rises to the heavens.</item>
        <item>The Gift of Truth excels all other Gifts.</item>
        <item>The greatest prayer is patience.</item>
        <item>The ignorant man is an ox. He grows in size, not in wisdom.</item>
        <item>The mind is everything. What we think, we become.</item>
        <item>The most valuable service is one rendered to our fellow humans.</item>
        <item>The non-doing of any evil, the performance of what\'s skillful, the cleansing of
            one\'s own mind: this is the
            teaching of the Awakened.</item>
        <item>The one who has conquered himself is a far greater hero than he who has defeated a thousand times a thousand men.</item>
        <item>The only real failure in life is not to be true to the best one knows.</item>
        <item>The root of all suffering is desire.</item>
        <item>The secret of health for both mind and body is not to mourn for the past, worry about the future, or anticipate troubles, but to live in the present moment wisely and earnestly.</item>
        <item>The simplicity of the good man is hard to follow. The simplicity of the evil man is easy to follow.</item>
        <item>The skilled man does not show off, but the man without knowledge usually show off.</item>
        <item>The tongue like a sharp knife... Kills without drawing blood.</item>
        <item>The true master lives in truth, in goodness and restraint, non-violence, moderation and purity.</item>
        <item>The virtues, like the Muses, are always seen in groups. A good principle was never found solitary in any breast.</item>
        <item>The virtuous man delights in this world and he delights in the next.</item>
        <item>The way is not in the sky. The way is in the heart.</item>
        <item>The whole secret of existence is to have no fear. Never fear what will become of you, depend on no one. Only the moment you reject all help are you freed.</item>
        <item>The wind cannot overturn a mountain. Temptation cannot touch the man who is awake, strong and humble. Who masters himself and minds the law.</item>
        <item>The wise have mastered body, word and mind. They are the true masters.</item>
        <item>The wise man tells you where you have fallen and where you yet may fall - Invaluable secrets! Follow him, follow the way.</item>
        <item>The wise ones fashioned speech with their thought, sifting it as grain is sifted through a sieve.</item>
        <item>There are no chains like hate...dwelling on your brother\'s faults multiplies your own. You are far from the end of your journey.</item>
        <item>There are only two mistakes one can make along the road to truth; not going all the way, and not starting.</item>
        <item>There has to be evil so that good can prove its purity above it.</item>
        <item>There is no fire like passion, there is no shark like hatred, there is no snare like folly, there is no torrent like greed.</item>
        <item>There is no fire like passion. No crime like hatred. No sorrow like separation. No sickness like hunger and no joy like the joy of freedom.</item>
        <item>There is nothing more dreadful than the habit of doubt. Doubt separates people. It is a poison that disintegrates friendships and breaks up pleasant relations. It is a thorn that irritates and hurts; it is a sword that kills.</item>
        <item>There is nothing so disobedient, as an undisciplined mind, and there is nothing so obedient, as a disciplined mind.</item>
        <item>There is pleasure and there is bliss. Forgo the first to possess the second.</item>
        <item>There isn\'t enough darkness in all the world to snuff out the light of one little
            candle.</item>
        <item>Those which arise dependently are free of inherent existence.</item>
        <item>Those who are free of resentful thoughts surely find peace.</item>
        <item>Those who are slaves of desires run into the stream of desires, even as a spider runs into the web that it made.</item>
        <item>Those who have failed to work toward the truth have missed the purpose of living.</item>
        <item>Those with good eye are inclined to fall into deep well.</item>
        <item>Though one should conquer a million men in battlefield, yet indeed, he is the noblest victor who has conquered himself.</item>
        <item>Though one should live a hundred years without wisdom and control, yet better, indeed, is a single day\'s life of one who is wise and meditative.</item>
        <item>Thousands of candles can be lit from a single candle, and the life of the candle will not be shortened. Happiness never decreases by being shared.</item>
        <item>Three things cannot be long hidden: the sun, the moon, and the truth.</item>
        <item>The mind has become freed from conditioning: the end of craving has been reached.</item>
        <item>Through zeal, knowledge is gotten; through lack of zeal, knowledge is lost.</item>
        <item>Time and tide wait for no man.</item>
        <item>To be angry is to let others\' mistakes punish yourself.</item>
        <item>To be idle is a short road to death and to be diligent is a way of life; foolish people are idle, wise people are diligent.</item>
        <item>To become vegetarian is to step into the stream which leads to nirvana.</item>
        <item>To conquer oneself is a greater victory than to conquer thousands in a battle.</item>
        <item>To defeat others is the starting point of hatred and vengeance.</item>
        <item>To force oneself to believe and to accept a thing without understanding is political, and not spiritual or intellectual.</item>
        <item>To forgive others is to be good to yourself.</item>
        <item>To insist on a spiritual practice that served you in the past is to carry the raft on your back after you have crossed the river.</item>
        <item>To keep the body in good health is a duty, otherwise we shall not be able to keep our mind strong and clear.</item>
        <item>To live a pure unselfish life, one must count nothing as one\'s own in the midst of
            abundance.</item>
        <item>To share happiness and to have done something good before leaving this life is sweet.</item>
        <item>To understand everything is to forgive everything.</item>
        <item>Today is better than two tomorrows.</item>
        <item>Unity can only be manifested by the Binary. Unity itself and the idea of Unity are already two.</item>
        <item>Until death there is nothing enough.</item>
        <item>Victory breeds hatred. The defeated live in pain. Happily the peaceful live, giving up victory and defeat.</item>
        <item>Virtue is persecuted more by the wicked than it is loved by the good.</item>
        <item>We are formed and molded by our thoughts. Those whose minds are shaped by selfless thoughts give joy when they speak or act. Joy follows them like a shadow that never leaves them.</item>
        <item>We are shaped by our thoughts; we become what we think. When the mind is pure, joy follows like a shadow that never leaves.</item>
        <item>We are what we think. All that we are arises with our thoughts. With our thoughts we make the world.</item>
        <item>Wear your ego like a loose fitting garment.</item>
        <item>What we are today comes from our thoughts of yesterday, and our present thoughts build our life of tomorrow: Our life is the creation of our mind.</item>
        <item>What we think, we become.</item>
        <item>What you are is what you have been. What you\'ll be is what you do now.</item>
        <item>Whatever words we utter should be chosen with care, for people will hear them and be influenced by them for good or ill.</item>
        <item>When it is impossible for anger to arise within you, you find no outside enemies anywhere.</item>
        <item>When one has the feeling of dislike for evil, when one feels tranquil, one finds pleasure in listening to good teachings; when one has these feelings and appreciates them, one is free of fear.</item>
        <item>When the aggregates arise, decay and die, O bhikkhu, every moment you are born, decay, and die.</item>
        <item>When the student is ready, the teacher will appear.</item>
        <item>When you come upon a path that brings benefit and happiness to all, follow this course as the moon journeys through the stars.</item>
        <item>When you realize how perfect everything is you will tilt your head back and laugh at the sky.</item>
        <item>Whoever sees me sees the teaching, and whoever sees the teaching sees me.</item>
        <item>With gentleness overcome anger.With generosity overcome meanness.With truth overcome deceit.With our thoughts we make the world.</item>
        <item>Without a beginning, there is nothing to worry about the end.</item>
        <item>Without health life is not life; it is only a state of langour and suffering - an image of death.</item>
        <item>Without recognition of death, how can there be any knowledge of it.</item>
        <item>Words have the power to both destroy and heal. When words are both true and kind, they can change our world.</item>
        <item>Work out your own salvation. Do not depend on others.</item>
        <item>You are the community now. Be a lamp for yourselves. Be your own refuge. Seek for no other. All things must pass. Strive on diligently. Don\'t give up.</item>
        <item>You are the source of all purity and impurity. No one purifies another.</item>
        <item>You cannot travel on the path until you become the path itself.</item>
        <item>You only lose what you cling to.</item>
        <item>You should respect each other and refrain from disputes; you should not, like water and oil, repel each other, but should, like milk and water, mingle together.</item>
        <item>You throw thorns, falling in my silence they become flowers.</item>
        <item>You too shall pass away. Knowing this, how can you quarrel?</item>
        <item>You will always be getting praise and blame, but do not let either affect the poise of the mind.</item>
        <item>You will not be punished for your anger, you will be punished by your anger.</item>
        <item>You yourself, as much as anybody in the entire universe deserve your love and affection.</item>
        <item>Your body is precious. It is our vehicle for awakening. Treat it with care.</item>
        <item>Your purpose in life is to find your purpose and give your whole heart and soul to it.</item>
        <item>Your work is to discover your work and then with all your heart to give yourself to it.</item>
        <item>Your worst enemy cannot harm you as much as your own thoughts, unguarded. But once mastered, no one can help you as much. Not even your father or your mother.</item>
    </string-array>
</resources>